Roberto Carlos Saavedra Baylón

<u>robertocarlos.saavedrabaylon@gmail.com</u> | <u>+34 644983798</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/rsaavedr</u> | <u>github.com/robertosaavedr</u>

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Statistics, Complutense University of Madrid 2018-2022 National University of Ireland, Maynooth (exchange year) 2020-2021

EXPERIENCE

R Programmer

February 2022 – May 2022

Quental Technologies, Madrid, Spain

- Programming in **R** in the Risk department of a Spanish Bank, I was in a team developing software to automate tasks for the Risk Analysts, such as a calculator for the expected monetary loss given a dataset of mortgages.

Data Analyst Intern

October 2021 – January 2022

Instituto de Estudios Fiscales, Madrid, Spain

- Internship in the Ministry of Finance of Spain, regression and descriptive analysis of Tax Income Data using SAS.

Data Analyst Intern

November 2019 – October 2020

Faculty of Statistical Studies, Madrid, Spain

- Analysis of data from surveys using **R**, **SPSS** and **SAS**.

OTHERS

Import Coffee, importcoffee.es

September 2018 - Present

Founder and Podcaster, Madrid, Spain

- Import Coffee is a programming club based in Complutense University of Madrid, was created with the purpose of bringing computer science and statistics together...

PERSONAL PROFILE

I have just finished my Bachelor's Degree in Applied Statistics in June 2022. I am a very proactive person, I have participated in the US Work and Travel program which allowed me to work for a summer in the United States, also, while in university I have worked as a lifeguard, cleaner, teacher and waiter. In my free time I like to read, travel, lift weights and hike...

SKILLS

R | PYTHON | SAS | SQL | GIT | MACHINE LEARNING | STATISTICAL MODELING | DATA VISUALIZATION